Subtitle Provide by dramacool.in Translator [Admin.@YNG]
تم توفير الترجمة بواسطة مترجم dramacool.in [Admin.@YNG]
♪Passing by where leaves fall and flowers fade♪
♪المرور حيث تتساقط الأوراق وتذبل الزهور♪
♪Chancing upon shooting stars and northern lights♪
♪الصدفة على النجوم المتساقطة والأضواء الشمالية♪
♪At this moment, I borrow the wind♪
♪في هذه اللحظة، أستعير الريح♪
♪To set sail for distant seas♪
♪للإبحار إلى البحار البعيدة♪
♪Rumors swirl close to my ears♪
♪تدور الشائعات بالقرب من أذني♪
♪Some laugh and say my dreams are wild♪
♪يضحك البعض ويقولون أن أحلامي جامحة♪
♪Yet I will not change my original aspiration♪
♪ولكنني لن أغير طموحاتي الأصلية♪
♪Even if it means running into a wall♪
♪حتى لو كان ذلك يعني الاصطدام بالحائط♪
♪I know the road to growing up brings pain♪
♪أعلم أن الطريق إلى النمو يجلب الألم♪
♪Still, I hold fast to the dream I cherish♪
♪ما زلت متمسكًا بالحلم الذي أعتز به♪
♪Never have I thought to yield♪
♪لم أفكر أبدًا في الاستسلام♪
♪Youth is meant to stand against the world♪
♪الشباب هو من المفترض أن يقف في وجه العالم♪
♪I've always longed♪
♪لقد تمنيتها دائما♪
♪To stand upon the highest peak♪
♪الوقوف على أعلى قمة♪
♪I've always wished♪
♪لقد تمنيت دائما♪
♪To cross a river wide and deep♪
♪لأعبر نهرًا واسعًا وعميقًا♪
♪In darkness, look up to see the sky turn clear♪
♪في الظلام، انظر إلى الأعلى لترى السماء تصبح صافية♪
♪Unyielding♪
♪لا يلين♪
♪The butterfly reborn from its cocoon must fly♪
♪الفراشة المولودة من شرنقتها يجب أن تطير♪
♪Like bamboo breaking forth, I chase dreams through hardship♪
♪مثل الخيزران الذي ينبت، أطارد الأحلام من خلال المشقة♪
♪Return to me, my dream♪
♪ارجع إليّ يا حلمي♪
♪Unyielding♪
♪لا يلين♪
♪My pure heart stays the same♪
♪قلبي النقي يبقى كما هو♪
♪You must face the wind♪
♪يجب عليك مواجهة الريح♪
♪And go where your heart leads♪
♪واذهب إلى حيث يقودك قلبك♪
♪Embrace the moonlight that belongs to you♪
♪احتضن ضوء القمر الذي ينتمي إليك♪
♪In the dark♪
♪في الظلام♪
=Voyage to Haihun, Season 1=
=رحلة إلى هايهون، الموسم الأول=
=Episode 11=
=الحلقة 11=
- Duke. - How is it?
- دوق. - كيف الحال؟
No sign of him in the north or south.
لا يوجد أي أثر له في الشمال أو الجنوب.
Li Qi has gone out of the city to search.
لقد خرج لي تشي من المدينة للبحث.
Duke.
دوق.
Well?
حسنًا؟
Nothing in the west either.
ولا يوجد شيء في الغرب أيضًا.
Search again.
ابحث مرة أخرى.
Comb through all of Hongnong if you must.
قم بتمشيط كافة أنحاء هونغ نونغ إذا كان لا بد من ذلك.
Yes.
نعم.
Duke, what has happened?
دوق، ماذا حدث؟
Wang Heng is missing.
وانغ هينغ مفقود.
Did you search the whole area?
هل بحثت في المنطقة بأكملها؟
He didn't come back last night.
لم يعود الليلة الماضية.
Duke, I searched all over the east of the city.
دوق، لقد بحثت في جميع أنحاء شرق المدينة.
Still no sign of Heng.
لا يزال لا يوجد أي علامة على وجود هنغ.
Lord Wang is usually very cautious.
اللورد وانغ عادة ما يكون حذرا للغاية.
He should be fine.
ينبغي أن يكون بخير.
Duke.
دوق.
Lord Shi is seething with anger.
اللورد شي يغلي غضبا.
He urgently needs you.
إنه يحتاج إليك بشكل عاجل.
What a strong smell of wine.
ما هذه الرائحة القوية للنبيذ!
How could Lord Wang be like this?
كيف يمكن للورد وانغ أن يكون هكذا؟
Lord Shi.
اللورد شي.
What's the matter?
ماذا جرى؟
You'll know once you see it.
سوف تعرف ذلك بمجرد رؤيته.
Heng.
هنغ.
Wake up!
استيقظ!
Wake up.
استيقظ.
Such disgrace.
هذا العار.
Lord Wang,
اللورد وانغ،
you're in such high spirits during the mourning period.
أنت في حالة معنوية عالية خلال فترة الحداد.
This is a setup.
هذا هو الإعداد.
Duke, Lord Shi,
دوق، اللورد شي،
please judge with clear sight.
يرجى الحكم برؤية واضحة.
Milord.
سيدي.
Yesterday, Lord Wang saved me
بالأمس، أنقذني اللورد وانغ
and escorted my sister and me home.
ورافقني وأختي إلى المنزل.
He is our savior.
إنه مخلصنا.
Last night,
ليلة أمس،
Lord Wang suddenly came
جاء اللورد وانغ فجأة
and said we should ride and drink together.
وقال لنا أنه ينبغي لنا أن نركب ونشرب معًا.
Out of courtesy,
من باب المجاملة،
my sister and I agreed.
أنا وأختي اتفقنا.
But unexpectedly,
ولكن بشكل غير متوقع،
something was slipped into our drinks.
لقد تم وضع شيء ما في مشروباتنا.
When I woke up,
عندما استيقظت،
we were already inside the carriage.
كنا بالفعل داخل العربة.
Wang Heng, how dare you
وانغ هينج، كيف تجرؤ؟
tarnish the Duke of Changyi's name during mourning
تشويه اسم دوق تشانغي أثناء الحداد
by committing such shameless acts!
من خلال ارتكاب مثل هذه الأعمال الوقحة!
Both witnesses and evidence are here.
الشهود والأدلة موجودة هنا.
What else do you have to say?
ماذا لديك أيضاً لتقوله؟
Using indecent means to bring someone down
استخدام وسائل غير لائقة لإسقاط شخص ما
has always been the most efficient way.
لقد كانت دائمًا الطريقة الأكثر فعالية.
Words are useless now.
الكلمات لم تعد ذات فائدة الآن.
I have been framed.
لقد تم تأطيري.
Humph.
همف.
Take care of these two ladies.
اعتني بهذه السيدتين.
Once the truth is uncovered,
بمجرد الكشف عن الحقيقة،
they will be given justice.
وسوف ينالون العدالة.
- Guards. - Yes.
- حراس. - نعم.
Wait.
انتظر.
He works for me.
إنه يعمل معي.
What right do you have to interfere?
ما هو الحق الذي لديك للتدخل؟
Sorry.
آسف.
Lord Shi, you uphold the law with strict fairness.
يا سيد شي، أنت تؤيد القانون بالعدالة الصارمة.
You have my respect.
لك احترامي.
But rest assured.
ولكن كن مطمئنا.
If one of us commits
إذا ارتكب أحدنا
such disgraceful conduct,
مثل هذا السلوك المشين،
we won't let it go unpunished.
لن نتركها تمر دون عقاب.
By law, he should be detained and questioned at once.
وبموجب القانون، يجب أن يتم اعتقاله واستجوابه على الفور.
Guards!
حراس!
- Yes!
- نعم!
Take Wang Heng away.
خذ وانغ هينج بعيدًا.
Lord Gong.
اللورد غونغ.
You two should head back first.
ينبغي لكما العودة أولاً.
Yes.
نعم.
Lord Gong,
اللورد غونغ،
I said I would handle this myself.
قلت أنني سأتعامل مع هذا الأمر بنفسي.
Why did you lock him up again?
لماذا قمت بسجنه مرة أخرى؟
Duke,
دوق،
the officials from Chang'an are here.
المسئولون من تشانغآن موجودون هنا.
Every word and action of yours is under their watch.
كل كلمة وفعل لك هو تحت مراقبتهم.
About what happened to Lord Wang today,
أما عن ما حدث للورد وانغ اليوم،
they caught him red-handed.
لقد تم القبض عليه متلبسا.
If you insist on shielding him,
إذا كنت تصر على حمايته،
how will the officials see it?
كيف سينظر المسؤولون إلى الأمر؟
They will surely think you are bending the law for him.
من المؤكد أنهم سيعتقدون أنك تنتهك القانون من أجله.
But Wang Heng must have been wronged.
لكن لابد أن وانغ هينغ قد تعرض للظلم.
I know that.
وأنا أعلم ذلك.
Lord Wang would never do such a thing.
لن يفعل اللورد وانغ مثل هذا الشيء أبدًا.
Right now, the priority is to find evidence,
في الوقت الحالي، الأولوية هي العثور على الأدلة،
so we can help Lord Wang clear his name.
حتى نتمكن من مساعدة اللورد وانغ في تبرئة اسمه.
Also,
أيضًا،
to keep Lord Wang in custody,
لإبقاء اللورد وانغ تحت الحراسة،
our men are more reassuring
رجالنا أكثر طمأنينة
than those from Chang'an, right?
من أولئك القادمين من تشانغآن، أليس كذلك؟
That being said,
ومع ذلك،
as long as Heng's name isn't cleared,
طالما أن اسم هينج لم يتم تبرئة،
I won't go anywhere.
لن أذهب إلى أي مكان.
Don't be reckless.
لا تكن متهورًا.
This isn't recklessness.
هذا ليس تهورًا.
It's loyalty.
إنه الولاء.
How could I abandon a friend in need?
كيف يمكنني أن أتخلى عن صديق وقت الضيق؟
You must not act rashly.
لا يجب عليك التصرف بتهور.
Countless eyes are watching.
هناك عيون لا تعد ولا تحصى تراقب.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
I'll move quietly.
سأتحرك بهدوء.
I won't alert the enemy.
لن أنبه العدو.
Hey, Senior.
مرحبا، كبير السن.
Senior, where are you going?
كبير السن، إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟
Who is there?
من هناك؟
Yes.
نعم.
Duke.
دوق.
Open the door.
افتح الباب.
You may all leave.
يمكنكم جميعا المغادرة.
- Yes.
- نعم.
Have you suffered?
هل عانيت؟
Thanks to Lord Gong,
بفضل اللورد غونغ،
he had our own men watching over me,
كان لديه رجالنا الخاصين يراقبونني،
so I wasn't harmed.
لذلك لم أتعرض لأذى.
Oh, right.
أوه، صحيح.
Last night,
ليلة أمس،
what exactly did you do?
ماذا فعلت بالضبط؟
(Wine)
(خمر)
Then I blacked out.
ثم فقدت الوعي.
You know what happened when I woke up.
هل تعلم ماذا حدث عندما استيقظت؟
It was this place.
لقد كان هذا المكان.
Tavern at the East Market in the city.
حانة في السوق الشرقي في المدينة.
What kind of evidence
ما نوع الدليل؟
is this?
هذا هو؟
It's the only thing that can prove my innocence.
إنه الشيء الوحيد الذي يمكنه إثبات براءتي.
It can help us find Shan.
يمكن أن يساعدنا في العثور على شان.
Bring me
احضرني
the bamboo slips from the last exam.
ينزلق الخيزران من الامتحان الأخير.
Bamboo slips?
زلات الخيزران؟
Yeah.
نعم.
Who are you?
من أنت؟
Stay back.
ابقى في الخلف.
What do you want?
ماذا تريد؟
I received an order.
لقد تلقيت طلبًا.
My apologies.
اعتذاري.
Stop right there.
توقف هنا.
You're walking right into my hands.
أنت تسير مباشرة إلى يدي.
You alone
انت وحدك
may not win against me.
قد لا يفوز ضدي.
Can handwriting really be recognized?
هل يمكن التعرف على خط اليد حقا؟
If the writing material is different,
إذا كانت مادة الكتابة مختلفة،
the pressure of the brushstroke can also differ.
يمكن أن يختلف ضغط ضربة الفرشاة أيضًا.
Bamboo slips are smooth and even.
انزلاقات الخيزران ناعمة ومتساوية.
But they're narrow and slender.
لكنها ضيقة ونحيلة.
The characters tend to be slimmer.
تميل الشخصيات إلى أن تكون أكثر نحافة.
Wooden tablets and silk strips
ألواح خشبية وشرائط حريرية
have a rougher surface.
لها سطح أكثر خشونة.
When writing on them, to keep the ink flowing smoothly,
عند الكتابة عليها، للحفاظ على تدفق الحبر بسلاسة،
you'd need to press harder.
سوف تحتاج إلى الضغط بشكل أقوى.
The brush tip would also feel sharper.
كما أن رأس الفرشاة سوف يصبح أكثر حدة.
However,
لكن،
the writer's overall style remains the same.
يبقى أسلوب الكاتب العام كما هو.
What habits does he have?
ما هي عاداته؟
His strokes are steady and weighty,
ضرباته ثابتة وثقيلة،
yet the structure of his characters is on the thin side.
ومع ذلك فإن بنية شخصياته ضعيفة.
When starting a horizontal line,
عند بدء خط أفقي،
the stroke tends to lift upward slightly.
تميل الضربة إلى الارتفاع إلى الأعلى قليلاً.
When making a rightward pressing stroke,
عند القيام بضربة ضغط باتجاه اليمين،
it rises a little as well.
ويرتفع قليلا أيضا.
Heng.
هنغ.
Come a bit closer.
اقترب قليلا.
That's him.
هذا هو.
(Tavern at the East Market in the city)
(حانة في السوق الشرقي بالمدينة)
Chen really shouldn't have done this.
تشين حقا لا ينبغي أن يفعل هذا.
Do you think Heng might have made a mistake?
هل تعتقد أن هينج ربما ارتكب خطأ؟
Isn't this handwriting comparison far too sloppy?
أليست هذه المقارنة بين خط اليد غير دقيقة إلى حد كبير؟
It's indeed hardly convincing.
إنه أمر غير مقنع حقا.
Senior.
كبير.
- Guards! - Keep it quiet.
- أيها الحراس! - أبقوا الأمر هادئًا.
Help me out first.
ساعدني أولا.
Senior.
كبير.
Where did you rescue her from?
من أين أنقذتها؟
From the hands of the one who killed my master.
من يد من قتل سيدي.
You might have seen him before.
ربما تكون قد رأيته من قبل.
What's his background?
ما هي خلفيته؟
Didn't Wang Heng tell you?
ألم يخبرك وانغ هينغ؟
He's with the court.
إنه مع المحكمة.
Other than me,
غيري،
there must be other spies around you.
لا بد أن يكون هناك جواسيس آخرين حولك.
Is it
هل هو
really Chen Bushi?
حقا تشين بوشي؟
She only has a few scrapes.
إنها تعاني فقط من بعض الخدوش.
She might also have been frightened.
ربما كانت خائفة أيضًا.
Nothing serious for now.
لا يوجد شيء خطير في الوقت الراهن.
Duke.
دوق.
We brought you some Lubing.
لقد جلبنا لك بعض التشحيم.
Join us for a bite.
انضم إلينا لتناول وجبة خفيفة.
If it truly is Chen,
إذا كان تشين حقا،
I have a way to test him.
لدي طريقة لاختباره.
I'm just not sure if it's proper.
أنا لست متأكدًا من أن ذلك صحيح.
I asked you here today
لقد طلبت منك هنا اليوم
because there's something to tell you.
لأن هناك شيئا أريد أن أخبرك به.
What is it?
ما هذا؟
It concerns Lord Wang's wrongful case.
يتعلق الأمر بقضية اللورد وانغ الخاطئة.
Those two women we met today...
هاتان المرأتان اللتان التقينا بهما اليوم...
What about them?
ماذا عنهم؟
They were attacked by an assassin.
لقد تم مهاجمتهم من قبل قاتل.
Did they die?
هل ماتوا؟
Thankfully,
ولحسن الحظ،
they were saved.
لقد تم انقاذهم.
Is that so?
هل هذا صحيح؟
However,
لكن،
her wounds were too severe,
كانت جروحها شديدة للغاية،
and she fainted.
وأغمي عليها.
But before she lost consciousness,
ولكن قبل أن تفقد وعيها،
she managed to say one thing.
تمكنت من قول شيء واحد.
What did she say?
ماذا قالت؟
She said
قالت
that the one who framed Lord Wang
أن الشخص الذي أوقع اللورد وانغ
is hidden among us.
مخفية بيننا.
No way.
مستحيل.
Among us?
بيننا؟
I trust
انا اثق
the three of you the most.
أنتم الثلاثة أكثر من غيركم.
Your job is to take turns protecting her.
وظيفتك هي التناوب على حمايتها.
When she wakes up,
عندما تستيقظ،
I'll question her myself.
سأسألها بنفسي.
You can count on us, Qi.
يمكنك الاعتماد علينا، تشي.
(Lodge)
(نزل)
Chen Bushi.
تشين بوشي.
Stop.
قف.
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
Why are you here so early?
لماذا أنت هنا مبكرا؟
Oh, I couldn't sleep, so I might as well do something.
أوه، لم أتمكن من النوم، لذلك ربما علي أن أفعل شيئًا.
You should get some rest early.
ينبغي عليك أن تحصل على بعض الراحة مبكرًا.
You're the thoughtful one.
أنت الشخص المفكر.
I'll bring you Lubing tomorrow.
سأحضر لك لوبينج غدا.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Keep a good watch.
حافظ على مراقبة جيدة.
Go on.
إستمر.
De Jiu.
دي جيو.
♪Watch the storm; hear the night rain fall♪
♪شاهد العاصفة؛ استمع إلى صوت هطول المطر في الليل♪
♪Till the light of dawn♪
♪حتى ضوء الفجر♪
♪A truth that cannot be spoken♪
♪حقيقة لا يمكن التحدث بها♪
♪Right and wrong matter♪
♪الصواب والخطأ مهمان♪
♪Yet I can't make the right choice♪
♪ولكن لا أستطيع اتخاذ الاختيار الصحيح♪
♪The lost player in the game♪
♪اللاعب الخاسر في اللعبة♪
♪Made a move by a twist of fate♪
♪لقد اتخذت خطوة بسبب تقلب القدر♪
♪The way back is lost, leaving nowhere to return♪
♪لقد ضاع طريق العودة، ولم يبق مكان للعودة♪
♪Borrow the endless cycles♪
♪استعارة الدورات التي لا نهاية لها♪
♪To fight for the most perfect outcome♪
♪القتال من أجل الحصول على النتيجة الأكثر مثالية♪
♪How to trace the threads and follow cause and effect♪
♪كيفية تتبع الخيوط واتباع السبب والنتيجة♪
♪Seeking a strategy without flaw♪
♪البحث عن استراتيجية خالية من العيوب♪
♪How to break free from this fated yet unforeseen lock♪
♪كيفية التحرر من هذا القفل المقدر وغير المتوقع♪
♪To live so as to shake the world♪
♪العيش من أجل هز العالم♪
♪With this journey, I gain a fiercer edge♪
♪مع هذه الرحلة، اكتسبت حافة أكثر شراسة♪
♪I've planned before I act countless times♪
♪لقد خططت قبل أن أتصرف مرات لا تحصى♪
♪Fatal danger turned into a jest♪
♪خطر قاتل تحول إلى مزحة♪
♪Through this road, I watch the endless rise and fall♪
♪من خلال هذا الطريق، أشاهد الصعود والهبوط الذي لا نهاية له♪
♪In the chapters lie ages of decay and bloom♪
♪في الفصول تكمن عصور من الاضمحلال والازدهار♪
♪Let us meet again♪
♪دعونا نلتقي مرة أخرى♪
♪One hurried path, and one at ease♪
♪مسار واحد سريع، ومسار آخر مريح♪